<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Hacker Within</title>
 <link href="http://thehackerwithin.github.com/berkeley/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://thehackerwithin.github.com/berkeley/"/>
 <updated>2014-01-22T08:35:15-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://thehackerwithin.github.com/berkeley</id>
 <author>
   <name>Hacker Within</name>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Meeting</title>
   <link href="http://thehackerwithin.github.com/berkeley/posts/first-meeting"/>
   <updated>2014-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://thehackerwithin.github.com/berkeley/posts/first-meeting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a planning meeting. Katy Huff, Ryan Bergmann, and Professor Rachel
Slaybaugh attended. Together we discussed a possible suite of useful software
practices to discuss this semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What is this?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed that part of the purpose of these meetings is to restart a
successful group that originated in Wisconsin, &amp;ldquo;The Hacker Within.&amp;rdquo; Ideally,
this meeting will facilitate sharing skills and best practices for
computational nuclear engineering applications. Last semester, we had a couple
such meetings. In spring semester I would like to share a number of skills for
scientific software development (testing, data management, version control,
literate programming etc. ) and to ask the rest of you to share the skills you
have as well. The goal will be to incorporate these practices into our
workflows. This would be a great venue for introducing new libraries, showing
off useful features of a neutronics code you&amp;rsquo;re using, or bringing up a
computational problem you&amp;rsquo;re having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What can be expected?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to try meetings with an agenda structured thus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; First, we will go around the room and attendees can introduce themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The meeting will start with one 30-40 minute talk on a topic of import to
 scientists who use software.  Particular emphasis is likely to be paid to
 topics useful to nuclear engineering researchers. To volunteer to give a
 talk, mention it at a meeting, or &lt;a href-&quot;mailto:katyhuff@gmail.com&quot;&gt;email
 Katy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The talk will be followed by a short period for questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; For up to 40 minutes, attendees will have the opportunity to give lightning
 talks on short topics. These may share a small skill snippet, demonstrate a
 computational issue you&amp;rsquo;re having with you&amp;rsquo;re research, or anything of
 interest to the group. Sometimes, lighting talk topics will be requested
 ahead of time on a theme (i.e., text editors). To give a lightning talk,
 just show up and speak up whe the time comes. If you like, letting Katy
 know ahead of time is always welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; After the meeting, attendees can hang around in the space and hack together
 on their research codes, if they like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;What are the topics?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topics for the first part of the semester will focus on reproducibility:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; command line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; gpus/cuda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; version control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; build systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; self documenting code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; cloud computing (amazon ec2, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; parallelism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; profiling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Lightning Talks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of good topics were identified for lightning talks or talk series. If
you&amp;rsquo;re interested in talking about these or something else, just come prepared.
If the talk you want to give is in a series, consider banding together a group
of folks who would like to give the other parts of the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; debugging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; libraries/linking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; scripted plotting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; exceptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; text editors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; licensing and export control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>